Des Gouttes & Associés



Arun Chandrasekharan

Partner

Deputy Secretary of the Supervisory Board CDB Former Member of the Board of the Geneva Bar Association Attorney at Law

Languages

English, (Swiss-)German, French, Italian

Contact Details

Telephone: + 41 22 704 30 50 arun.chandrasekharan@desgouttes.ch

Expertise

Corporate and Contracts

Arun Chandrasekharan primarily advises, negotiates, drafts and resolves disputes related to service contracts, such as mandate agreements, distribution agreements, joint venture agreements, licensing agreements, outsourcing agreements, manufacturing agreements, supply agreements, management agreements, employment agreements or general consulting contracts both in international and domestic relations.

He assists clients on transactions concerning the sale of companies or assets (including real estate transactions), investment in companies, transfer of technologies. He advises, negotiates, drafts and resolves disputes pertaining banking matters (loan agreements, asset management, trade finance, etc.), shareholders' agreements, share or asset purchase agreements, investment agreements, convertible loan agreements and related agreements.

With his own personal experience on Boards of Directors, Arun regularly handles issues of corporate law including corporate housekeeping and corporate restructuring.

Litigation and Arbitration

Arun Chandrasekharan disposes of a vast experience in dispute resolutions both before courts in Geneva and other cantons as well as in arbitration and mediation. He regularly acts as sole arbitrator, party appointed arbitrator and mediator both in ad hoc proceedings as well as in institutional arbitrations/ mediations (International Chamber of Commerce, Swiss Arbitration Centre, Arbitral Tribunal of the Swiss Association of Asset Managers).

Education

2000	Admission to the Geneva Bar (ranked 2 nd best)
1998	University of Geneva, Licence en droit
1995	Mathematisch-Naturwissenschaftliches Gymnasium Rämibühl, Zurich, Matura

Professional Experience

2002	Partner, I	Des Goutte	es & A	ssociés	
2001-2002	Associate	, Des Gou	ttes &	Associés	
1998-2000	Trainee Associés	Lawyer,	Des	Gouttes	&

Other Activities		
Since 2021	Deputy Secretary of the Supervisory Board CDB	
Since 2019	Vice-President of the ADR Commission of the Geneva Bar Association	
Since 2018	Member of the Commission en matière d'honoraires d'avocat	
Since 2014	Member of the Board of Directors of Dynawealth Management Ltd.	
Since 2010	Member of the Board of Directors of SI Domaine du Parc SA	
2015-2021	Member of the Board of Directors of the Geneva Bar Association	

2002-2004 Member of the Board of Directors of

Imtix Sangstat (Switzerland) GmbH

Enforcement

Arun Chandrasekharan regularly ensures the enforcement of foreign and national decisions and clients' rights by means of civil seizure of assets, criminal proceedings on behalf of financially harmed clients or recognition proceedings. He is a member of the International Fraud Group.

Memberships

Geneva Bar Association (OdA), Swiss Bar Association (SAV), International Fraud Group (IFG)